James Smith

Mail: lee.smith870327@gmail.com

Personal Website: https://webdevych.github.io/

GitHub: https://github.com/webdevych

Summary

A highly skilled individual full stack developer who is comfortable with both frontend and backend programming. I have been working as a web developer for 7 years and managed many projects for my clients satisfying 100%.

Strong organizational and project management skills, good problem-solving skills, attention to detail, and excellent verbal communication skills are my specific features.

Experience



Frontend Developer (React/Next)

Ronday

Aug 2021 - Present (1 year +)

- Built and deployed a pattern-library for the Ronday UI using storybook, semantic HTML elements and **CSS**
- Developed a reusable template based on pattern-library using React, Next.js
- Developed Ronday website and admin site based on templates
- Tested website using jest, testing framework and Cypress, Selenium for end-to-end testing.
- Integrated Auth0, Amazon Cognito for authentication.
- Collaborated backend team to interact API calls.
- Contacted product designers for an immediate update and change.

Skills: React, Next.js, Redux toolkit, Tailwind CSS, Storybook, JavaScript, Typescript



Full Stack Developer

Upwork

Aug 2020 - Jul 2021 (1 year)

- Developed websites and mobile applications for over 20 clients.
- Designed and developed integrated management system from scratch.
- Helped multiple clients finalize problematic projects by providing the needed expertise to bring projects to release.
- Built mission-critical applications that scale and support thousands of users.
- Integrated social media tools and SDKs into various websites and mobile applications.

Skills: React, Next.js, React Native, Flutter, Typescript, Shopify, React Native, Python, Django, Node, Express, Asp.net, Elixir, Phoenix, MQTT, WebRTC, Blockchain, Solidity, JavaScript



Senior Frontend Developer

Inmetrics

Apr 2019 - Jun 2020 (1 year 3 months)

- Implemented new responsive, mobile-first approach which increased mobile traffic by 30%.

- Implemented websites, mobile applications, and landing pages from concept through deployment.
- Standardized all output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.
- Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility.
- Developed standard and ad hoc reports in graph format as required.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments

Skills: React.js, Next.js, TypeScript, Node.js, Express.js, React Native



Web Developer

Straits Interactive

Feb 2017 - Nov 2018 (1 year 10 months)

- Oversaw full lifecycle of software development for 5 projects with 100% on time delivery while staying 5% under budget.
- Designed processes for cleanup and performance improvement that minimized downtime by 9%.
- Assisted the design team by delivering pixel-perfect implementation of websites for over +7 projects.
- Introduced new technologies into the company's production team by resulting 15% increase sales.
- Implemented HR business management model using react full stack by decreasing completion period 5%.

Skills: Python, Django, JavaScript, React



Full-stack Developer

Baufest

Jul 2014 - Oct 2016 (2 years 4 months)

- Involving in writing application-level code to interact with APIs, web services using Ajax, JSON, and XML.
- Developing CSS, SASS styles on all the pages of an application, and positioning of objects etc.
- Engaged web application development from scratch with Laravel / AngularJS
- Performed bug fixes and maintained the code for mobile applications using Objective-C and Java

Skills: Java, Android, Angular, JavaScript, HTMK



🏷 Software Developer

BR Softech Pvt. Ltd.

Jun 2013 - Feb 2014 (9 months)

- Participated in internal website building based on PHP, MYSQL and JavaScript.
- Big data process using no SQL database

Skills: PHP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL

Education



The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology

Master's degree, Computer Science Apr 2013 - May 2018

Licenses & Certifications

Complete Web Developer in 2019 - Zero To Mastery Academy

Cambly English Course - Cambly Inc 26cbb9c3

Skills

Frameworks: React/Next • Vue • Node/Express • Laravel • Django • Flutter/React Native

Languages: JavaScript • PHP • Python

Databases: MySQL • MongoDB • PostgreSQL Other: Firebase • Docker • Webpack • GitHub